

SKILLS

SQL Server	8+ yrs
Java	3+ yrs
Javascript	3+ yrs
Python	4+ yrs
Html/CSS	3+ yrs
React	3+ yrs
GIT	3+ yrs

CONTACT

- 70 Endicott St. #601
 Norwood, MA 02062
- 508-208-0210
- pearsonk27@gmail.com



KRIS PEARSON

Software Engineer

PROFILE

Software Engineer with a strong technical and analytical skills and professional demeanor.

Strong interest in big data, automated QA, and application development.

Has worked in many different companies with many different methodologies and personalities. Adapting while keeping the same likable personality and positive attitude is an undeniable strength.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SBE Vision

Software Engineer

4/2022 - 9/2022

A large micro-service architecture built with Java Spring Boot applications orchestrated by Kubernetes.

- Creation of a full-trip tests of the stack managed by a REST API application to host requests called in a larger Postman Collection hit regularly by a Newman Runner.
- · Maintain the Microsoft Excel Adapter/Plugin
- Build out reporting for Elasticsearch

Technologies include:

- Java Spring Boot for all backend services
- SQL Server and MongoDB for data persistence
- Angular for the easy frontend interaction
- Kubernetes + Docker for deployments
- gRPC, REST API, and Rabbit for service communication
- · Git for versioning
- Git Lab for CI/CD

Vestmark

Full Stack Software Engineer

2019 - 2022

Application development on a Java Spring Boot proprietary investment platform.

 Various user stories implementing functionality deemed necessary by the product team

EDUCATION

Boston College

Bachelor of Arts - Economics, Minor in Mathematics

Main curriculum priority was in quantitative/analytical courses such as Econometrics, Statistics, Probability, Integrated Math and Physics, and Sports Econometrics.

Many courses required aptitude in programming languages and software such as STATA, Excel, R, Python, LaTeX and more.

Chosen to be a Research Assistant where in empirical research on media and digital imagery markets, including research on industry background and data processing and analysis.

Also participated in the Investment Club, Lacrosse Club, and studied abroad.

AWARDS

2018

Employee of the Year Award Awarded for my integral role in improving the product offerings to fit the largest client's needs.

2018

Patrick J Martin Committe Chair

Identified employees throughout the organization who displayed talent and passion in their given roles, working with 5 committee members to select award recipient.



- · Correct bugs in Vestmarkone during release level testing
- · Build Selenium tests in the separate Python project
- Fixes to client specific data integrations utilizing a proprietary data manipulation API
- · Attend and present at regular Sprint Reviews

Technologies include:

- Java, SQL Server, and React/Javascript for application development
- · Terraform, AWS and Docker for application deployment
- · Python using the Selenium library for automated web testing
- Apache Camel and Karaf for Data Integration micro-services development
- · Git for versioning
- Jenkins for CI/CD

Achievements include:

- Development of new data integration framework using Apache Camel and Karaf
- Promoted from Associate SWE to SWE in January 2021
- Product Level Security Substitutes (with team) User stories demanded use of React, Java, and SQL Server.

Connance / Waystar Senior Data Integration Engineer

2017 - 2019

Develop solutions to solve hospital client revenue cycle needs.

- Code and test client specific work aiming to manage sensitive hospital patient account data
- Build tools and automation meant to increase the effectiveness and efficiency of the team
- Build and design new frameworks for managing common client needs, train engineers on how to use and improve the framework

Technologies include:

- Transact SQL for report building, database updates, and functional logic in business rules
- SSIS and Powershell for data integration jobs
- C# and Perl for data manipulation during data ingress and egress
- · Windows Task Scheduler and SQL Server Agent for job scheduling
- TFS for versioning

Achievements include:

CERTIFICATIONS

OCA - Java SE 8 Programmer

Issued October 2020

COURSES

2020

Java for Data Scientists Essential Training

2020

Learning JDBC

To find the most up-to-date list of my courses I've taken, visit my LinkedIn linked to from my portfolio at kristoferpearson.com or follow my QR Code on this resume.

- Assisted in building and improving ActionRules a replacement for Connance's business rules engine. ActionRules is a configurable batch SQL script moving accounts to various debt collection stages according to various actions taken, inclusion criteria, and exclusion criteria specified by the client in the UI.
- · Built out UI utilizing MVC framework
- Built and helped test performance improvements needed to handle the load given by Waystar's largest client, who is 10 times larger than any other client serviced.
- · Made Production Engineer Team Lead (3/2019)
- Won Employee of the Year award (12/2018)
- Patrick J Martin Award Committee Chair (9/2018)

Analyst / Product Manager Definitive Healthcare

Key technical contributor on many projects building out the company's product offerings and increasing efficiency and effectiveness in various company operations.

- Managed, assisted, and trained (7) analysts in the methodology used to build the proprietary user-friendly web-based application, which consolidates various types of healthcare provider focused data to aid healthcare focused industries.
- Managed and assisted the development and maintenance of software.
- Delegated or solved all product errors. Quickly identified the source of any errors, determined the level of skill needed to solve the problem, and assigned accordingly.
- Team lead for all new technology, product rollouts (one product rollout per month), coding methodology, and database administration.

Technologies include:

- SQL Server for ETL, report generation and business logic
- · Windows Command line
- · SSIS, C#, Visual Basic for ETL and report generation
- · Visual Studio for UI development
- · Powershell for reporting job execution
- ASP.NET, HTML, CSS for UI development and data entry form development
- · Microsoft Access for data entry form development

Achievements include:

- Developed SSIS package and method to build automatically refreshing reports for clients, significantly improving efficiency of company FTP site development process (estimated 75% less time needed to complete/maintain FTP sites). Process utilized SQL Server view generation and a C# script.
- Developed re-useable PowerShell script that loads data to a client's SFTP server that retries after connection failures, logs output to a .txt file, emails client to confirm data load completion, can be set to run every month, drastically cutting down on employee work necessary

PERSONAL PROJECTS

WebExecuter

Project I use to automatically pay my town utility/cable bills. UI starts jobs on my Raspberry Pi that hosts the database, frontend, and scripts

cheatsheet.io

CRUD app utilizing Java Spring Boot, React, and Postgresql. The frontend and backend are each standalone projects.

wordlecheat

My attempt at finding the optimal strategy at Wordle. The application "plays the game" over and over again with different strategies, recording what happens and analyzes the data

These projects can be found on my Github page. You can get there by going to my portfolio at kristoferpearson.com or following my QR Code on this resume.



- Developed a Master Data matching process using a fuzzy lookup, used to link client data to company data. Regression analysis built into the script to weigh methods used by success rate.
- Optimized the company's Population Health queries by adding primary keys and indexes to the tables, as well as redesigning the queries so that there is a high amount of parallelism. Prior to changes, 1 query took 2 minutes, 4 of the same queries at once took 8 minutes, after the changes, 1 query took 4 seconds, 4 of the same queries at once took 8 seconds.